ABOUT ME

Creative software developer looking to work with a dedicated team. Enthusiastic to learn, spending my free time reading up on libraries and techniques. I am obsessed with surmounting engineering hurdles and hunting down pesky bugs. Over 6 years experience working in IT.

AWARDS & PUBS.

Airman of the Year - 961st AACS, Kadena AB, 2010

Journal Publication -

Jackson, E. D.; Green, S. C.; Prieto, A. L. Electrochemical Performance of Electrodeposited Zn4Sb3Films for Sodium-Ion Secondary Battery Anodes. ACS Applied Materials & Interfaces 2015, 7 (14), 7447–7450.

SKILLS

Languages:

React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Python, Bash

Operating Systems:

Linux, Windows

DevOps:

Git, Svn

Misc:

Agile methodology

CONTACT

scott96707@gmail.com

github.com/scott96707

in/scott96707/

scott96707.github.io

ScottGreen

Full Stack Developer | Denver, CO

WORK HISTORY

(Aug. 2019 - Present)

QUALITY ASSURANCE ENGINEER - CSG Systems

- Troubleshot dozens of production and development defects. Found bugs in Perl, JavaScript and SQL statements and supplied bug-fixed code to developers.
- Wrote several scripts in Bash and Python to automate repetitive and risky tasks.
- Worked in an international team in an Agile/Scrum framework.
- Helped manage Linux servers, adding a tool to check App status and load testing monitoring tools.

(Sep. 2017 - Sep. 2018)

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT - T4S Partners

- Designed multiple back-end systems, including an auto-assignment ticketing system, REST API integration, and email parsing, using a declarative scripting language.
- Coordinated testing, deployment of features, and bug fixes for a SaaS business product.
- Troubleshot production-affecting service outages. Determined causes and implemented solutions, minimizing downtime and improving client relations.
- Worked in a team to develop and maintain custom systems for multiple clients.

(June 2008 - June 2012)

COMPUTER TECHNICIAN - USAF | Kadena, Japan & Beale, CA

• Operated in teams composed of varied specialties to maintain two AWACS aircraft and a DCGS system.

PROJECTS

Face Recognition App

React - Node.js - Express.js - PostgreSQL - JavaScript - HTML - CSS

Register and login users to a PostreSQL database, input the URL of a photograph, and any human faces in the picture will be outlined with a border. Uses the free Clarifai API to identify faces in the photograph. Hosted on Heroku.

Star Wars App

React - JavaScript - HTML - CSS

Responsive front-end displaying information which is retrieved from a free Star Wars API endpoints (tested using Postman) and displayed on individual cards. Cards are interactive.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

(Sep, 2019)

AWS - Certified Cloud Practitioner

(May, 2016)

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, CHEMISTRY - Colorado State University